What is claimed is: 
     
         1 . A system comprising:
 a memory storing instructions; and   a processor communicatively coupled to the memory and configured to execute the instructions to:
 direct an imaging device included in a computer-assisted surgical system to detect, during a surgical procedure performed with the computer-assisted surgical system, fluorescence emitted by a population of fluorophores present at a scene, wherein:
 the imaging device comprises a detector having a plurality of distinct regions each configured to detect the fluorescence emitted by the population of fluorophores, and 
 the directing the imaging device to detect the fluorescence comprises directing the plurality of distinct regions to sample the fluorescence in succession over a time period that is less than a lifetime of the fluorescence to generate a plurality of fluorescence image signals, each region included in the plurality of distinct regions generating a distinct fluorescence image signal included in the plurality of fluorescence image signals; and 
 
 determine, based on the plurality of fluorescence image signals, the lifetime of the fluorescence. 
   
     
     
         2 . The system of  claim 1 , wherein the directing each region included in the plurality of distinct regions to sample the fluorescence in succession over the time period comprises activating each region of the plurality of distinct regions in succession over the time period. 
     
     
         3 . The system of  claim 1 , wherein the processor is further configured to execute the instructions to:
 direct the imaging device to detect, during the surgical procedure, additional fluorescence emitted by an additional population of fluorophores present at the scene, wherein the directing the imaging device to detect the additional fluorescence comprises directing the plurality of distinct regions to sample the additional fluorescence in succession over a time period that is less than a lifetime of the additional fluorescence to generate a plurality of fluorescence image signals, each region included in the plurality of distinct regions generating a distinct additional fluorescence image signal included in the plurality of fluorescence image signals; and   determine, based on the detected additional fluorescence, a lifetime of the additional fluorescence.   
     
     
         4 . The system of  claim 3 , wherein:
 the population of fluorophores emit the fluorescence in response to a first set of pulses of fluorescence excitation illumination having a first wavelength configured to excite the population of fluorophores; and   the additional population of fluorophores emit the additional fluorescence in response to a second set of pulses of fluorescence excitation illumination having a second wavelength configured to excite the additional population of fluorophores, wherein the first wavelength is different from the second wavelength.   
     
     
         5 . The system of  claim 4 , wherein:
 the directing the imaging device to detect the fluorescence comprises directing the imaging device to detect the fluorescence in sync with the first set of pulses; and   the directing the imaging device to detect the additional fluorescence comprises directing the imaging device to detect the additional fluorescence in sync with the second set of pulses.   
     
     
         6 . The system of  claim 1 , wherein the imaging device comprises an endoscope. 
     
     
         7 . The system of  claim 1 , wherein the processor is further configured to execute the instructions to determine, based on the determined lifetime of the fluorescence, an identity of the fluorophore. 
     
     
         8 . The system of  claim 7 , wherein the processor is further configured to execute the instructions to configure, during the surgical procedure and based on the determined identity of the fluorophore, operation of the computer-assisted surgical system. 
     
     
         9 . A method comprising:
 directing an imaging device included in a computer-assisted surgical system to detect, during a surgical procedure performed with the computer-assisted surgical system, fluorescence emitted by a population of fluorophores present at a scene, wherein:
 the imaging device comprises a detector having a plurality of distinct regions each configured to detect the fluorescence emitted by the population of fluorophores, and 
 the directing the imaging device to detect the fluorescence comprises directing the plurality of distinct regions to sample the fluorescence in succession over a time period that is less than a lifetime of the fluorescence to generate a plurality of fluorescence image signals, each region included in the plurality of distinct regions generating a distinct fluorescence image signal included in the plurality of fluorescence image signals; and 
   determine, based on the plurality of fluorescence image signals, the lifetime of the fluorescence.   
     
     
         10 . The method of  claim 9 , wherein the directing each region included in the plurality of distinct regions to sample the fluorescence in succession over the time period comprises activating each region of the plurality of distinct regions in succession over the time period. 
     
     
         11 . The method of  claim 9 , further comprising:
 directing the imaging device to detect, during the surgical procedure, additional fluorescence emitted by an additional population of fluorophores present at the scene, wherein the directing the imaging device to detect the additional fluorescence comprises directing the plurality of distinct regions to sample the additional fluorescence in succession over a time period that is less than a lifetime of the additional fluorescence to generate a plurality of fluorescence image signals, each region included in the plurality of distinct regions generating a distinct additional fluorescence image signal included in the plurality of fluorescence image signals; and   determining, based on the detected additional fluorescence, a lifetime of the additional fluorescence.   
     
     
         12 . The method of  claim 11 , wherein:
 the population of fluorophores emit the fluorescence in response to a first set of pulses of fluorescence excitation illumination having a first wavelength configured to excite the population of fluorophores; and   the additional population of fluorophores emit the additional fluorescence in response to a second set of pulses of fluorescence excitation illumination having a second wavelength configured to excite the additional population of fluorophores, wherein the first wavelength is different from the second wavelength.   
     
     
         13 . The method of  claim 12 , wherein:
 the directing the imaging device to detect the fluorescence comprises directing the imaging device to detect the fluorescence in sync with the first set of pulses; and   the directing the imaging device to detect the additional fluorescence comprises directing the imaging device to detect the additional fluorescence in sync with the second set of pulses.   
     
     
         14 . The method of  claim 9 , wherein the imaging device comprises an endoscope. 
     
     
         15 . The method of  claim 9 , further comprising:
 determining, based on the determined lifetime of the fluorescence, an identity of the fluorophore.   
     
     
         16 . The method of  claim 15 , further comprising:
 configuring, during the surgical procedure and based on the determined identity of the fluorophore, operation of the computer-assisted surgical system.   
     
     
         17 . A system comprising:
 a memory storing instructions; and   a processor communicatively coupled to the memory and configured to execute the instructions to perform a process comprising:
 accessing a plurality of fluorescence images representative of fluorescence detected by a detector having a plurality of distinct regions, wherein:
 each fluorescence image is representative of the fluorescence detected by a distinct region of the detector, and 
 the plurality of fluorescence images are captured in succession over a time period that is less than a lifetime of the fluorescence; and 
 
 determining, based on the plurality of fluorescence images, a lifetime of the fluorescence. 
   
     
     
         18 . The system of  claim 17 , wherein the determining the lifetime of the fluorescence comprises:
 generating a decay curve based on a combination of the plurality of fluorescence images; and   determining the lifetime of the fluorescence based on the decay curve.   
     
     
         19 . The system of  claim 17 , wherein the process is performed during a surgical procedure performed with a computer-assisted surgical system. 
     
     
         20 . The system of  claim 19 , wherein:
 the computer-assisted surgical system comprises an endoscope; and   the plurality of fluorescence images are captured by the endoscope.
